hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation playlist so
continuing with our topic on the test
automation obstacles let's look at the
next automation obstacle which is called
the to-do list and here we have got two
tables one is the the to-do tasks and
one is the completed tasks now the
challenge here is we need to drag and
drop each row from these twoo tasks into
the completed tasks in a certain order
okay so we need to drag uh in the
numerical order so we'll first drag the
first task then uh the second one and
then the third
one okay and then the fourth one and
then the the fifth and then the sixth
okay and then the obstacle will be
completed so that's what you need to do
using tosa now we have already seen how
we can drag and drop elements okay so we
can use that in the table also we can
drag and drop the rows but here we need
to do this uh number of times as you can
see six times right and in a certain
order so that's the challenge here right
so let's see how we can do this in
tosa so first of all we need to scan uh
our page okay so let's go ahead and do
that I'm going to scan the application
now and basically we need to scan uh the
two tables which uh we'll be working on
right so here if I scan this page you
can see these two tables the to-do task
and the completed tasks okay so these
are the two tables which I need to scan
so let me rename this module to this
particular
obstacle and I am going to do it right
here okay and then I'm going to save
this and close the module right so our
module is created here with both the
tables and now let's go back to our test
case folder and here we are going to
create a new test case again with the
same obstacle uh number okay and here we
are done going to use our module which
we have scanned earlier
right so uh once you drag this module
here so what we need to do is uh we need
to drag each row from the too task table
to the completed task table right but
before we do that we also need to use
another uh functionality here or another
feature which is called the reputation
property right so that uh we need to do
for for our table right and in order to
do that uh we need to create a folder
okay so I'm going to create a folder
inside my test case and uh we are going
to rename this okay so we'll re rename
this to
repetition okay and then uh we are going
to drag our test step inside this now
what this will do is it will basically
repeat it the number of times which we
will uh Define for this particular
folder right and as you know we have to
repeat our drag and drop step six times
so I'm going to set this repetion to six
okay so that's what you need to do and
then uh this particular test step will
be executed six times okay now if we go
inside the table uh and we'll look at
this page you can see that uh we need to
drag a according to the ID right so we
need to drag the first uh task which has
got id1 and then the second task which
has got the id2 so we need to work
around this ID column right so what
we'll do uh we'll go to the column and
we'll select the ID here okay and then
in the cell value uh we are going to put
something called
reputation okay so this is an expression
which returns you the value of the
reputation property okay so whatever
reputation uh value is being set here uh
which means if uh we are running this
for the first time the repetition
property value or the repetion
expression value would be one and then
two then three like that it will keep on
changing this particular value of the
cell right so uh that will decide the ID
which will be 1 2 3 4 5 six and that is
what we want right we want to drag um
each task with a different ID each time
right now um in the value U again we
will put the drag operation here because
we want to drag this particular row with
this particular ID and we will change
the action mode to input okay now once
that is done we just need to drop it
into the completed task table right so
here we can use the drop
expression okay uh we don't need to
select any row and colum because we just
want to drag it into the table right so
now this will be repeated uh six times
because we have set the property to six
for the reputation folder and then it
will get this particular value of
reputation and uh it will select the ID
based on that okay and then it will drag
it and drop it into the completed tasks
so let's see if it works or not but this
is how we can uh complete this
particular obstacle okay so let's run
this in
scratchbook so as you can see it has
started dragging the first row and then
dropped it into the completed task table
it will do it for each of the task based
on the ID so this is running on a
repetition six times and it will drag
and drop all the six rows
right okay and you can see uh the
obstacle was successfully completed
right so this is how you can drag and
drop a rows from a table and drop it
into another table and then using the
repetition property you can put your
test steps inside a folder and then you
can select uh some unique column like
the ID which has got the numbers 1 to
six so you can put the reputation
property value inside that so that uh
these tasks are dragged and dropped in a
certain
order that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video